imagine that you were born in India the
seventh biggest country in the world and
the most spiritual country in the world
the land known for its diverse cultures
and enchanting Landscapes you wake up in
the morning stand up from your bed and
open the window and the first thing you
notice is a huge mountain of trash which
is so high that it has warning lights on
top of it to prevent aircraft and
helicopters from crashing inad stepping
out outside the first thing you see is
extra crowded streets filled with street
food prepared with a lot of oil and
spices the smell of which makes you feel
dizzy after a few minutes you notice
that it's hard to breathe and you start
coughing like a chain smoker even if you
haven't smoked a cigarette in your
entire life in no time you understand
the cause of your sickness which is all
around you that that and that is typical
India and it really really
sucks so let's start from the beginning
the first place you're going to visit is
the Mount Everest of trash also named
gazipur l fill tons of trash are
transported daily from different parts
of the city to this landfill which was
initially designed as a temporary
solution to India's waste problem
however the problem wasn't solved and
with time it only got bigger today the
gazipur landfill has grown to be bigger
than 40 soccer fields and taller than
the Taj Mahal which is around 2113 ft
tall every year a few times the
landfills Catch Fire and destroy the
houses nearby because of the burned
plastic and other chemicals the smell
becomes unsupportable especially in the
high heat the pollutant produced from
burning intoxicates the water and soil
which fever has a huge impact on the
Local's
Health despite the fact that India has a
terrible environment even Indians are
afraid to marry women from gazipur
because it's believed that no women
older than 16 can carry a healthy child
under such conditions it is practically
impossible to prevent such fires because
no fire truck can reach the top of the
mountain so the firefighters only
extinguish the most available Parts
usually the base of the mountain with
the highest Parts being unreachable when
there's no fire scavengers make their
way through the piles of trash these
people make their living by collecting
recyclable materials and manually
selecting plastic from trash making a
few dollars a day which helps them not
die of
hunger
because of the terrible ecology a lot of
people suffer from various diseases that
mutilate their bodies and take away
their chance to live a normal
[Music]
life all right but why not just leave
and go to a much more livable City the
short answer is that some people just
can't afford it a lot of the them were
already born into poverty like their
neighbors whose only source of existence
is separating plastic from trash others
just don't care accepting this type of
existence as normal yes Indians accept a
lot of things as normal that would be
unacceptable in any other Society for
example the open statistics say that
close to 594 million people which is 48%
of the population in India practice open
defecation that's half of the population
dumping over 65 million kilos of poo in
the streets Fields or Rivers every
single day even though in 2015 the
Indian government built half a million
home toilets a lot of people still
prefer to fertilize the soil outside
helping to spread a ton of diseases
through water and air that phenomenon
confused the sanitary inspectors who
decided to investigate household toilet
usage very quickly they discovered that
most of the toilets were used as storage
rooms that's because many Indians
believed that having a toilet inside the
house was absolutely unhygienic however
open defecation isn't the only practice
used by Indians to make their country
uninhabitable another usual thing is
spitting caused by this thing called pan
Masala which is an Indian traditional
chewing mixture usually consisting of
spices mixed with bittl nuts and slate
lime when consumed it's supposed to
provide a sense of relief after meals
serving as a mouth freshener however
Indians mix it with tobacco which has a
terrible effect on health increasing the
risk of oral cancer among many others
chewing pan Masala produces a lot of
saliva which has a black brownish color
eventually you could see a lot of people
spitting like camels directly on the
streets and even in public transport
leaving everywhere disgusting Brown
puddles reminding you of blood all right
let's say that we got tired of people
who defecate and speit on the streets
and we decided to change the atmosphere
and relocate to the cultural center of
India Delhi with the hope that it should
be better there at least the streets
should be cleaner and people more
cultural finally you're in Delhi but
once you arrive it becomes clear that
you haven't reached your destination yet
yes here in Delhi the government puts
more effort into preventing Street
pollution by installing trash bins but
that doesn't really work because people
steal them and sell them a scrap metal
for a few pennies you'll not be
surprised to learn that Delhi is also
the city with the highest level of air
pollution in the world the scientist
concluded that spending a single day
outside in these conditions is like
smoking 50 cigarettes on this highway
located near Delhi the smoke was so
dense that drivers couldn't even see
where they were going as a result more
than 25 cars were involved in a massive
accident on this 3D air pollution map we
can check the air quality worldwide in
real time blue and green colors mean
that the air quality in this region is
good yellow means that the air quality
is moderate orange and red mean that the
air quality is unhealthy and purple
means that the air quality is very
unhealthy and even hazardous now if we
take a look at the United States we
notice that the color is blue and green
if we jump to Europe we can see that the
color is mostly green which means that
in this region the air quality is pretty
good but let's now take a look at India
here we can see that the color has
changed to orange red and the air index
pollution is 20 times higher than the
norm which means that any contact with
outdoor air should be avoided at all
another problem is Indian Street food
and the sellers who ignore any hygiene
or safety Norms whatsoever
there are countless videos where Street
vendors prepare the food with bare hands
and in the same oil and that's not the
worst you get diarrhea and you get
diarrhea and you get diarrhea everyone's
getting diarrhea this ignorance in
combination with the street pollution
could leave you at high risk of getting
sick from germs or bacteria nearly
poisoned because of a traffic exhaust
fumes and on the ede of desperation you
decide to move to one of the oldest
cities in the world where people are
much more humble and haven't forgotten
about God the spiritual capital of India
theany still on the way you sense a
smell so unpleasant that it couldn't
even be compared with the smell from
gazipur however you still can't figure
out what it is but shortly after it
becomes clear that this is a combination
of FAL hashish and burning corpses you
see veran SE besides being the spiritual
capital of India is also famous for its
River the gangas which is the dirtiest
river in the world on the banks of the
gas bodies have been cremated for
hundreds of years that's because Hindus
believe in the cycle of birth death and
rebirth so the act of cremation is seen
as releasing the soul from the body so
that it can continue its journey in the
afterlife or be reincarnated that's why
tens of thousands of bodies are cremated
there every single year and the ashes
are lowered into water but because of
poverty not every Indian has a necessary
firewood to entirely burn the body
therefore dozens of half bured bodies
flow on the river crowding together and
rotting until recovered by volunteers
who often need to even dive into the
water the bodies that couldn't have been
recovered wash ashore were there usually
eaten by hungry dogs or crows however it
is prohibited to burn pregnant women and
children under 13 these people are
instead died to a stone and drown in the
GES not too long ago the wife should
have been burned along with her husband
after he passed away this tradition was
known as Sati and was declared illegal
only 90 years ago even though there are
thousands of dead bodies drowned in the
GES River every single month a lot of
people are comfortable washing in the
river and even drinking directly from it
because of filthy conditions and
people's indifference diseases that
civilized society has forgotten about
for hundreds of years can still be found
here for example leprosy also known as
Hansen's Disease which is considered
eliminated in most European countries
still exists in India with 120,000
people suffering from it every single
year yes you could say that not all
Indians are like that there are actually
normal people who would really love to
make a change but let's make a guess
right now what country do you think this
location is in the signs are written in
Hindi so it should be India right wrong
that's a street called Little India in
one of the cleanest countries in the
world Singapore in Singapore it's
illegal to spit in coffee shops or
markets but it's also illegal on public
roads sideways and any other place
that's open to the public if you break
this law you'll be slept with a fine of
up to $1,000 what about littering
firsttime offenders face a fine of up to
$1,000 Singapore dollars repeat
offenders will be fined up to2 2,000
Singapore dollars and subject to
corrective work order but even that
doesn't help when there are problems
with the environment and comfort of the
city people often point the finger at
the government however that's not the
case with India where the fish rots from
the tail down and it all begins with
people's mentality you see from ancient
times in India there was a cast system
established the highest casts are the
ones who litter and the lowest are the
ones who clean however the amount of
trash produced by multiplying this logic
by billions of people would be too much
for even an army of cleaners to handle
although Indians are known for keeping
their homes and bodies clean they're
indifferent to what happens over their
fence another problem is that before
Indians joined the global food system
all waste was environmental either
decomposed naturally was burned or the
leftovers were eaten by cows this is
where the habit of throwing everything
under food came from with the ition of
plastic Glass and Metal people still
have the tendency to throw everything
under food but now cows can't eat it and
it doesn't decompose the last reason is
the passive propaganda even if the
country occasionally airs advertisements
on federal channels warning of the
dangers associated with waste this is
completely insufficient in today's world
on paper the maximum fine for throwing
trash on the street is $6 but in
practice no one is taking it seriously
even Indians don't know it exists so I
didn't any fines when you lit it no
there are no fines here you can just
throw it anywhere nobody gives two shits
about it India is a perfect example of
the broken windows Theory which states
that visible signs of disorder and
misbehavior in an environment encourage
further disorder and misbehavior leading
to Serious crimes where simply put if
one window is broken and isn't repaired
soon more windows will be broken in the
neighborhood because people would stop
being civilized if their environment
isn't and we see such an example in
India where the more garbage is thrown
on the streets the more garbage will be
thrown my words can be confirmed by an
experiment which was made in India
volunteers found a dirty Street cleaned
it up and painted the walls and it
helped people stopped littering there
they did the same thing with a dirty
Store Wall transforming it into a public
toilet and it helped as well people
stopped being on the wall what about the
smog pollution if we take a look on this
graph we can notice that in October and
November the level of air pollution
increases hundreds of times but car are
driving all year round and factories
don't go on vacation so what's the
matter the thing is the majority of
smoke does not appear in the city it's
coming from Punjab and harana which are
two main agricultural regions in the
country rice is grown here which
requires a huge amount of water for
irrigation and at some point so much
water was required that there was a risk
of serious environmental consequences
therefore the authorities passed a law
According to which it is forbidden to
plant rise before the start of the rainy
season which starts in August so the
Harvest period has shifted to the
beginning of October and because of this
the farmer has less time to prepare for
the new season so in order to clean the
fields faster they simply began to burn
them every year burning fields are
producing a huge Cloud which is blown
directly into Delhi by the winds and
mixed with exhaust fumes and
construction dust recently they tried to
bend the burning of the fields but the
law was not accepted we could say that
everything we talked about in this video
is the concern of politicians on the
other hand if the Indians don't want to
make a change the politics wouldn't take
any action until something Clicks in the
minds of the entire half a billion
people nothing will change or perhaps as
soate