India's most politically powerful and
populous region is also its most
backward and you know nobody wants to
talk about it. This part of India has
the most voters, the most members of
parliament and the most influence on who
becomes prime minister. It's called the
cow belt. But don't let the name fool
you. Behind the holy cows and the temple
bells, this region is drowning in
poverty, violence, illiteracy, religious
extremism, and political manipulation.
And it's dragging the rest of the
country down with it. Let's get straight
into it. The cowbelt is a stretch of
northern India that includes U Pradesh,
Bihar, Madya Pradesh, Rajasthan, Jarand,
Chhattisgar, and parts of Harana and
Udarakand. These states form the
Hindspeaking heartland of India where
the cow is considered sacred and Hindu
nationalism is thriving. It's the BJP's
fortress, Narendra Modi's comfort zone
and it's also where democracy goes to
die a slow painful death along with
basic manners, hygiene and many other
things. Let's start with some numbers. U
Pradesh alone sends 80 MPs to
parliament. That's more than the entire
south of India combined. Add Bihar's 40
MPs, Madya Pradesh's 29, Rajasthan's 25,
and the rest of the cow belt, and you're
looking at a political juggernaut.
Whoever wins the cowbell basically wins
India. There's a reason why Modi and the
BJP keep education levels low in this
area so that they can ply them with
misinformation and brainwash
them. Now, here's the problem. This
region holds massive power, but it's in
complete shambles. Let's talk about
poverty. According to the latest
multi-dimensional poverty index, Utar
Pradesh, Bihar, Jarand and Madya Pradesh
are among the poorest states in India.
In Bihar, over half the population lives
in poverty. These are people who don't
have access to clean water, working
toilets, basic health care or decent
housing. In 2023, a report showed that
three out of every 10 children in these
states are malnourished. In some
districts of Uttar Pradesh and Bihar,
it's even worse. Now education the
literacy rates in these states are
embarrassingly low. Bihar's literacy
rate is around 63% compared to 94% in
Kerala. Utar Pradesh isn't doing much
better hovering around 73% which might
sound okay until you remember that this
is basic literacy just the ability to
read and write your name. When it comes
to actual education quality most
government schools in these states are
underfunded, understaffed and
practically falling apart. The annual
status of education report has been
sounding the alarm for years. In rural
UP, for instance, more than 50% of
children in grade 5 can't even read a
second grade level
text. Now, let's talk about health.
Maternal mortality, infant mortality,
and access to health care are all worse
in the cow belt. In U Pradesh, the
maternal mortality rate is over 200
deaths per 100,000 live births, double
the national average. Hospitals lack
basic equipment. Doctors are in short
supply. And in many villages,
superstition still replaces science.
What about jobs? Youth unemployment is
rampant. A 2022 report found that Bihar
and Utar Pradesh had some of the highest
youth unemployment rates in India. Even
those with degrees, many of them from
shady private colleges, end up driving
rick shaws or working as daily wage
laborers. In Bihar, during one of the
government job exams, millions of people
applied for just a few thousand
vacancies. Some PhD holders applied for
low-level jobs. That's how desperate
things
are. And here's where it gets even more
twisted. Despite all of this, despite
the poverty, the illiteracy, the
hopelessness, the people here keep
voting for the same parties, especially
the BJP. Mod's face is everywhere. Yogi
Adityanath, a hardline monk turned
politician, is the chief minister of
Udar Pradesh and is openly pushing a
Hindutva agenda. The BJP doesn't win
here in spite of the misery. It wins
because of it. Here's how it works. When
people are poor, uneducated, and
desperate, it's easier to distract them
with religious nationalism. Instead of
jobs, you give them riots. Instead of
development, you give them temples.
Instead of questioning power, they're
told to protect the cow. Cow politics is
no joke here. Cow slaughter is banned in
most cowbelt states and Muslims, dolls
and Christians have been lynched on mere
suspicion of transporting beef. These
lynch mobs often walk free. Sometimes
they're even celebrated. Remember
Pukhan, Aklak, Tabresari, their names
should haunt us. But here they're
brushed aside as necessary sacrifices
for a Hindu raashtra. And the media,
don't even get me started. Most of the
national Hindi language media outlets
are based in Delhi or Noa, right next to
the cow belt. and they've become
full-time cheerleaders for the ruling
party. Watch a Hindi news channel for 5
minutes and you'll see anchors foaming
at the mouth about Pakistan love jihad
or how Modi is saving Parat. You won't
hear a word about hunger or
unemployment. A message to Paly Sharma
and the God media. You are actively
making your country worse by blindly
cheering Modi and the BJP's terrible
policies. But why is this region so
backward in the first place? Let's go
back in history. The gangetic plains of
the cow belt were once the cradle of
Indian civilization. Ancient cities like
Veronasi, Patna and Aayodia were centers
of learning, culture and commerce. In
fact, it was one of the wealthiest
places in the world during the ancient
and early medieval periods. But over
time, especially during colonial rule
and after independence, investment
shifted elsewhere toward coastal states
like Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Gujarat
and Carnitaka. The cowbelt was left
behind. Postindependence cast politics
became the dominant force here. Leaders
like Lalu Prasad Yadav in Bihar and
Mayawadi in Udar Pradesh rose by
mobilizing lowercast votes. These were
important movements for social justice,
but they didn't always lead to good
governance. In fact, corruption,
nepotism, and criminalization of
politics became widespread. Then came
the BJP with a new formula. Combine
upper cast consolidation, Hindu
nationalism, and cow worship, and you
get a winning machine. This is not just
about religion, it's about controlling
people. When you convince the majority
that they're under threat from
minorities, you don't have to answer any
real questions. Why do you think Modi
rarely does unscripted interviews and so
the cowbell becomes a factory of
majoritarianism? Freedom of speech is a
joke. Disscent is punished. Journalists
who ask tough questions are jailed,
beaten, or worse. Activists disappear.
Even comedians aren't safe. Ask Munawar
Farooqi. But the irony is the people
suffering the most are the very ones who
keep the BJP in power. They don't have
clean drinking water. They don't have
decent jobs, but they have WhatsApp,
Twitter, and other social media
platforms where every problem is blamed
on Muslims, liberals, China, or the
West. We've all seen the angry netzens
flooding the comment sections. Let's be
real. This is not just about the BJP.
The Congress, regional parties, and the
entire political system have failed this
region again and again. But the BJP has
perfected the art of weaponizing that
failure. Take Uttar Pradesh again. This
is a state that sends the most MPs to
parliament. It's home to the Ganga to
Aayodia to Varanasi Mod's own
constituency and yet it ranks near the
bottom in every human development index.
In some parts of the state, especially
in Bundelkand and eastern UP, conditions
are so bad that families sell their
daughters into marriage just to survive.
And it's not just a rural problem. Even
urban areas like Kpur, Patna, and Bopal
are struggling with broken
infrastructure, terrible pollution, and
rising crime. Remember the investor
summit in Bopal where the lunch hall was
stormed and destroyed by hundreds of
attendees just because there was some
free curry and samosas. Meanwhile, Yogi
Aditanath is building the Ram Mandir.
Modi is unveiling statues. The media is
clapping. And the people, they're still
waiting for a better life. Compare this
to southern states like Kerala or Tamil
Nadu. Yes, they have their own issues,
but their literacy rates, health
indicators, and social welfare systems
are miles ahead. In fact, the south
often subsidizes the cow belt through
central taxation but gets insulted for
being too westernized or
anti-Hindu. Speak Hindi, not Tamil, they
say while receiving Tamil
taxes. So the hard truth which many
nisens don't want to hear is that the
cow belt is holding India back not just
economically but socially and
politically. It's a place where
democracy is being replaced by
demagoguery, where blind faith is
rewarded and critical thinking is
punished. And unless we fix it, the rest
of India will be dragged down too. This
isn't about looking down on poor people.
It's about demanding better for them.
They deserve jobs, schools, hospitals,
not just cow statues and hate speeches.
But for that to happen, we have to stop
glorifying this region as the soul of
India. Because right now, it's not the
soul, it's the rot. If you enjoyed this
video, then please like, comment, and
subscribe.