All right, today we’re unpacking a geopolitical
mess that’s spicier than a street food stall’s
hottest curry. We’re talking about how China’s
had enough of India’s antics and is tightening the
noose around it, with the recent Pahalgam attack
giving Beijing a golden ticket to speed things up.
India’s been acting like the neighborhood bully,
pushing around smaller countries like Sri Lanka,
Maldives, Nepal, and Bangladesh, but it made
a fatal error: painting China as its rival in
the West’s eyes. Big mistake. China’s been
quietly playing savior to India’s victims,
and now, with Bangladesh’s new leadership
and some jaw-dropping military moves, India’s
cornered itself into a hopeless spot. Stick
around, because this is about to get wild.
I’m Harrison Blackwell, and you’re watching Info
Safari. If you haven’t subscribed yet, hit that
subscribe button and join the crew exposing the
chaos of global politics. If you understand Hindi,
unlike me, be sure to explore the Hindi version
of Info Safari—find the link at the top of the
description. Also, in today's shout-out, a
big thanks to Wayne Mak for another Super
Thanks. Your support truly means the world.
India’s been strutting around South Asia like
it owns the place, throwing its weight at
smaller neighbors. Take Sri Lanka: in 2022,
when its economy tanked, India offered a $4
billion aid package, but it came with strings—New
Delhi wanted control over key ports and energy
projects. Sri Lanka, desperate, had to play along,
but China swooped in with debt restructuring
and investments through its Belt and Road
Initiative. By 2024, Sri Lanka’s Hambantota
Port was firmly under Chinese influence,
a slap in India’s face. Then there’s Maldives.
India tried to strong-arm the island nation
into prioritizing its military presence, but
President Mohamed Muizzu, elected in 2023,
kicked out Indian troops by May 2024 and signed
defense pacts with China instead. Nepal? Oh,
India’s been meddling there forever, but in 2024,
Kathmandu joined the BRI, cozying up to Beijing
for infrastructure deals worth $2.5 billion.
And Bangladesh—here’s where it gets juicy.
When Sheikh Hasina’s government fell in August
2024, Muhammad Yunus stepped in as interim leader.
Unlike Hasina, who often bent to India’s pressure,
Yunus is all about development and zero tolerance
for New Delhi’s bullying. Bangladesh is a
game-changer because of its location—right next to
India’s vulnerable “Chicken’s Neck,” the Siliguri
Corridor, a 20-kilometer-wide strip connecting
India’s mainland to its northeastern states.
If that gets cut off, India’s in deep trouble.
China’s been pouring money into Bangladesh,
with $1.4 billion in BRI loans in 2024 alone,
building roads, ports, and power plants. But
here’s the kicker: reports from The Hindu
in April 2025 revealed China’s constructing an
airbase in Bangladesh’s Rangpur district, just 300
kilometers from the Chicken’s Neck. That’s not a
neighborly gesture; it’s a strategic chokehold.
Now, let’s talk about the Pahalgam attack. On
April 22, 2025, terrorists struck Baisaran meadow
in Jammu and Kashmir, killing 26 people,
mostly tourists. As the days are passing,
it is getting clearer and this attack is
looking more like an inside job. New Delhi,
led by Narendra Modi, saw this as a chance to
flex its muscles and rally domestic support
by playing the anti-Muslim card. Big blunder.
India banned Pakistani ships from its ports,
suspended the Indus Water Treaty, and closed
the Wagah-Attari border. Modi thought Pakistan
would back down. Spoiler alert: it
didn’t. Pakistan’s got China’s backing,
and China’s not here to play nice.
Let’s zoom out. For the past six months,
China’s been outmaneuvering India like a chess
grandmaster. First, there was the bombshell in
January 2025 when Pakistan and China inked a
deal for 40 J-35 fifth-generation fighter jets.
India’s Tejas program, meanwhile, is a
laughingstock—decades behind. Pakistan’s air
force, bolstered by Chinese tech, outclasses
India’s aging Sukhois and even its 36 French
Rafales. And here’s a cheeky thought: maybe
France is secretly glad India’s Rafales haven’t
faced Pakistan’s J-10C yet. No one wants their
shiny jets embarrassed by Chinese engineering.
Then came the news that shook India’s defense
analysts: Bangladesh’s Rangpur district,
already hosting that Chinese airbase,
reportedly had ISI operatives active,
according to a report by Hindustan Times. India’s
intelligence network in Bangladesh is strong,
but it’s scrambling. Modi’s hate-mongering
after Pahalgam backfired spectacularly. Instead
of isolating Pakistan, it pushed Bangladesh
closer to China. A retired Bangladeshi general,
Fazlur Rahman, even suggested that Dhaka should
team up with China to seize India’s northeastern
states if India attacks Pakistan, as noted by
NDTV on May 3, 2025. Bangladesh’s government
distanced itself, but the message was clear:
India’s neighbors are done with its attitude.
China’s strategy is like a boa constrictor—slow,
deliberate, and suffocating for India. Through the
BRI, it’s locked in Sri Lanka, Maldives, Nepal,
and now Bangladesh. The China-Pakistan Economic
Corridor, valued at $62 billion as of 2024,
gives Pakistan’s Gwadar Port a direct line to
Beijing’s wallet. Gwadar’s not just a port; it’s
a Chinese fortress in all but name. Do you think
China will sit idly by if India threatens that
investment? Not a chance. Beijing’s state media,
like Global Times, has been framing Pahalgam as a
local issue, subtly backing Pakistan’s narrative
and dismissing India’s claims of cross-border
terrorism. China’s ambassador to India,
Xu Feihong, tweeted condolences after
the attack but avoided naming Pakistan,
a diplomatic middle finger to New Delhi.
India’s dug itself into a hole. Modi’s
post-Pahalgam saber-rattling was meant to boost
his popularity, but it’s trapped him. Pakistan’s
not retreating—its military briefed political
parties, vowing a “robust response” to any Indian
“misadventure.” Indian public opinion, whipped
into a frenzy by Modi’s rhetoric, won’t let him
back down without losing face. Meanwhile, China’s
arming Bangladesh, with $500 million in military
aid to Dhaka in 2024, per DNA India. India’s
northeastern states are a powder keg, and the
Siliguri Corridor’s never looked more fragile.
Think of India as a guy who picked a fight at a
bar, only to realize the bouncer’s got
friends—big, scary friends. Sri Lanka,
Maldives, Nepal, and Bangladesh are slipping
into China’s orbit. Pakistan’s air force is
ready to make India’s Rafales look like paper
planes. And that Chinese airbase in Rangpur?
It’s like Beijing parked a tank in India’s
backyard. India thought it could play the
victim card with Pahalgam, but all it did was hand
China a megaphone to amplify its influence.
What’s next? India’s running out of
moves. Its economy’s shaky—growth slowed,
while China’s BRI pumps billions into its
neighbors. Modi’s domestic posturing can’t
hide the fact that India’s surrounded. In the next
few months, expect more Chinese military deals,
maybe even a naval base in the Maldives, as DNA
India speculated. India’s intelligence might try
to stir trouble in Bangladesh, but with Yunus in
charge and China watching, that’s a long shot.
The Pahalgam drama didn’t just expose India’s
weaknesses; it accelerated its downfall.
So, there you have it—India’s geopolitical
blunders laid bare. China’s playing the long game,
and India’s helping it win. If you enjoyed
this breakdown, smash that like button,
share this video, and subscribe to Info Safari for
more hard-hitting truths. Drop a comment with your
thoughts—can India wiggle out of this mess,
or is it game over? See you in the next one.