Friends, today's video is going to be
very important as we'll be discussing
three major news. First, when Indian
foreign secretary Vikram Misri was asked
about the Indian fighter jets being
destroyed by Pakistan, here's what he
had to say. Second, what are US and
French officials saying regarding the
Indian fighter jets that were reportedly
shot down by Pakistan? And friends, US
officials are also becoming concerned
that Chinese equipment is outperforming
Western equipment. And third, India is
also claiming that it has shot down
Pakistan's F-16s in Rajasthan and has
even captured a pilot. And most
importantly, what is the US vice
president saying about the IndiaPakistan
conflict? This video is going to be very
interesting. Friends, whatever I say,
I'll back it up with proof. If you think
I'm lying, feel free to DM me on
Instagram with the evidence and I will
definitely correct my mistake. Friends,
many of you watch the videos without
subscribing. Please make sure to
subscribe. I put in a lot of effort to
create neutral and fact-based videos on
defense and
geopolitics. I present news articles as
proof to support my content. So, please
subscribe and like this video. It has
now been over 30 hours since the second
attack on Pakistan by India, which was a
drone strike. Yesterday when I made a
video I mentioned that Pakistan was
claiming to have intercepted 29 Israeli
made Harop loitering munitions launched
from India and they even presented
visual evidence as proof. At that time
Indian officials meaning the Indian
government and military leadership were
not accepting this claim. However, today
Indian foreign secretary Vikram Misri
has confirmed that yes, India did carry
out drone attacks on Pakistan because
Pakistan had earlier conducted drone
strikes in Indian Punjab. So according
to him, this was a retaliatory strike.
However, Pakistani officials have
rejected this statement. Friends, in
this ongoing IndiaPakistan conflict,
finding the real news has become
extremely difficult. It usually takes
about 12 hours after any development for
the actual facts to emerge and it
requires a lot of research. Now India is
claiming that it intercepted Pakistani
drones in Indian Punjab. But so far I
haven't come across any proof. No drone
parts, no visuals, nothing has surfaced.
If anyone has proof, please DM me on
Instagram. Now let's talk about the
Indian foreign secretary's press
conference. During the press conference,
a journalist asked him, "Pakistan is
claiming to have shot down five Indian
fighter jets. What is your response? Did
Pakistan actually destroy five Indian
jets or not? Please give a yes or no
answer to this." Mr. Vikram Misri
responded that no comments will be made
on this matter for now. He said that the
answer will be given at the appropriate
time regarding whether Indian fighter
jets were shot down or not. You can
listen to his statement yourself to hear
exactly what he said.
So friends, from the statement of the
Indian foreign secretary, it seems clear
that he doesn't want to lie because if
Indian fighter jets had not been shot
down, he would have outright said so.
His silence suggests that jets were
indeed shot down. Look, no country's
foreign minister or foreign secretary
can lie openly because these officials
represent their country at the United
Nations. So, I believe that my Indian
friends now have their proof that
fighter jets were indeed downed. Now,
let's move to the second news story,
which comes from a BBC article, an
outlet that to some extent is even
considered pro-India.
They reported that they have found
evidence of the wreckage of a Rafal
fighter jet. According to BBC verify, in
one clip geoloccated by BBC verify to a
field near the city of Bethinda in
India's Punjab state, troops can be seen
collecting debris from what experts
suggest was a crashed jet. We have also
located two further clips from the same
location filmed at night. One shows
debris in the field, while another shows
a projectile catching fire in the sky
and then fire in an open field.
Justin Crump, a former British Army
officer who now runs the risk
intelligence company, Cibilene, told BBC
Verify that the wreckage appears to be
from a French air-to-air missile of the
type used on both Mirage 2000 and Rafale
jets, both of which are operated by the
Indian Air Force. Another image
circulating on social media shows a tail
fin marked with BS001 and Rafale on it.
A Google reverse image search reveals
that this image is not from any older
incident. It appears to be new and
genuine. Friends, remember one thing.
These days, even if people lie a lot,
it's also easier to uncover the truth.
You can now verify whether images are
fake or real. And the wreckage verified
by BBC is from Bethinda in Indian
Punjab. This news, which was published
by Reuters, concerns the downing of
three fighter jets in Jamu and Kashmir.
Following this, French intelligence
officials revealed in an interview with
CNN that there is confirmation of one
Rafal jet being shot down by Pakistan.
While investigations are still ongoing
regarding Pakistan's claim of three jets
being downed, you can read the article
for details. The New York Times has
reported that the Indian Air Force has
suffered heavy losses. In addition, US
military officials in an interview with
Reuters stated that it is confirmed that
Chinese-made fighter jets shot down two
Indian aircraft. The US is closely
monitoring this development, especially
as Chinese equipment appears to be
outperforming Western systems in this
incident. Here is a quote from US
officials. The performance of a leading
Chinese fighter jet against a western
rival is being closely watched in
Washington for insights into how Beijing
might fare in any potential conflict
over Taiwan or in the broader
Indo-Pacific region. One US official
speaking on condition of anonymity said
there is high confidence that Pakistan
used Chinese-made J10 aircraft to launch
air-to-air missiles against Indian
fighter jets, bringing down at least
two. Another official added that one of
the Indian jets that was shot down was a
French-made Rafale fighter aircraft.
Both officials confirmed that Pakistan
did not use its US supplied F-16 jets
manufactured by Loheed Martin in the
shootown. Meanwhile, India is claiming
that it has shot down a Pakistani F-16
and captured the pilot. But let's keep
one thing in mind. Pakistan is not
allowed to use its F-16s outside of its
own territory. This restriction is part
of the agreement between Pakistan and
the United States when the F-16s were
sold. According to that deal, Pakistan
can only operate F-16s within its own
airspace. So the claim that a Pakistani
F-16 was shot down inside Indian
territory, specifically in Rajasthan,
does not hold up under scrutiny. It's
highly unlikely and probably incorrect.
Friends, that was the analysis. Make
sure to share your thoughts in the
comments because friends, in today's era
of social media, it doesn't take long
for proof, visuals or evidence to come
out. If India has truly captured the
pilot of a Pakistani F-16, then they
should present him to the world as
proof. Anyway, the real developments
related to this will surface soon.
Similarly, if Pakistan has actually
carried out drone attacks in Jammu and
Kashmir, then evidence of that will also
come to light in due time. That's all
for today's update. Please subscribe and
like this video.