Just one day before the IndiaPakistan
war on May 6th, India reportedly made an
official request to France to provide
the source code for the Rafale fighter
jets. This was documented in an article
published on india.com dated May 6th.
However, France declined India's request
stating it would not share the Rafale's
source code. Following this, as you're
aware, during the night of May 7th and
8th, India launched missile attacks on
nine Pakistani positions. These strikes
were carried out using the very same
French Rafale jets armed with scalp
cruise missiles and hammer precisiong
guided munitions. But on that same night
while operating within its own
territory, India reportedly lost six
fighter jets to Pakistani action. These
included three French Rafal jets, one
Sue30 MKI, one Mig 29 and one Mirage
2000. This shocking development occurred
despite the Rafal being among the most
advanced jets in India's inventory.
After the conflict ended and a ceasefire
was established, India once again
requested the Rafal source code from
France. This time applying more
diplomatic pressure. However, France
once again refused to provide the source
code. So friends, let's analyze what
this source code actually is, why it's
so important, and how not having it may
have affected the Indian Rafaels during
the conflict. We will also look into the
challenges India is now facing and
whether the recent crash of three Rafals
could be linked to this lack of source
code access. Moreover, what impact will
this have on India's recent deal to
acquire 26 Rafalem naval variant
aircraft from France? Make sure to watch
the video till the end as the upcoming
analysis will be deeply informative and
help you understand the critical
implications of these developments.
Friends, many of you watch the videos
without subscribing. Please make sure to
subscribe. I put in a lot of effort to
create neutral and fact-based videos on
defense and
geopolitics. I present news articles as
proof to support my content. So, please
subscribe and like this
video. Welcome back. The source code is
essentially the brain of any modern
combat aircraft. It controls critical
software systems such as radar
integration, weapons targeting, data
fusion and electronic warfare
capabilities. Without access to this
code, India cannot independently
integrate indigenous weapons or modify
system functionalities. It will have to
depend on French cooperation for any
such upgrades or adjustments. Friends, I
believe now you have a clear
understanding of what a source code is.
Now let's talk about why it's so
important. What loss India suffered due
to its absence and what advantage
Pakistan may have gained. You see any
modern military today whether it's the
Navy, Air Force or Army operates within
a networkcentric warfare framework
during times of conflict. For example,
the United States uses data link 16
which enables real-time exchange of data
between aircraft, naval ships, ground
forces, and command centers.
One major advantage the US has is that
most of its military equipment is
indigenously produced. Whether it's
fighter jets, naval vessels, or awax
aircraft, they are all integrated into a
centralized system and continuously
share realtime data with each other
during combat operations. As I mentioned
in one of my previous videos, Pakistan
also has a data link system known as
data link 17. Through this system,
Pakistan's three military branches,
Army, Navy, and Air Force are able to
share realtime data seamlessly. For
example, consider the incident where a
Pakistani J10C, while staying within its
own territory, shot down an Indian
Rafale. This was possible due to
efficient data sharing and coordination.
The J10C is a light to mediumweight
fighter jet and according to estimates,
its radar has a maximum range of around
180 km. The Rafale was reportedly shot
down using a PL17 missile which has a
range of 185 km. So how was this
possible? It was because Awax aircraft
flying behind the front line had already
locked onto the enemy aircraft and
shared that targeting data with the
J10C. Once the J10C fired the missile,
those same Awax aircraft helped guide
the missile to its target. This entire
operation illustrates what we call the
ABC system. Locked by A, launched by B,
guided by C. This integrated combat
system effectively links groundbased
radars, airborne early warning aircraft
and fighter jets into one cohesive unit.
A hallmark of true network ccentric
warfare. Currently, India operates four
different data links whereas ideally a
country should have just one unified
data link system. The first is the air
force network followed by the integrated
air command and control system which
enables real-time coordination between
aircraft surfaceto-air missile systems
and ground control units. Then comes
data link 2 which facilitates secure
communication between Indian navy
warships and Indian air force aircraft.
The fourth is the thales link used in
Rafale fighter jets. However, this Thaly
system is not integrated with India's
other systems because France has not
provided the source code for it. As a
result, whenever India operates Rafale
fighters, they cannot fully integrate
with groundbased air defense systems. To
avoid friendly fire or interference,
either these air defense systems must be
turned off or the Rafals must fly away
from areas covered by groundbased
defense units. Moreover, Rafale jets
cannot share data with India's existing
Awax platforms either. As I've mentioned
before, India already has a limited
number of Awaxs and Rafale's radar has a
maximum range of around 200
km. The jet Spectra electronic warfare
suite also has a limited range of about
100 to 150 km. In contrast, Pakistan's
Awax and EW aircraft offer coverage of
up to 500 km and are fully integrated
under a single system. Data Link 17. All
of Pakistan's defense equipment operates
within this unified data network.
Additionally, China has provided
Pakistan with the source code for the
J10C fighter jet, allowing it to be
fully integrated with Pakistan's Awax
and EW platforms. This integration
provides Pakistan with a significant
advantage in networkcentric warfare
capabilities. Just like India has a
large number of Russian-made equipment
which does not integrate well with
Western systems because Russian gear is
fundamentally different from Western
technology. Pakistan's military benefits
from Chinese equipment that is more
compatible with Western systems. For
example, Pakistan's airborne early
warning and control aircraft include the
Swedish Saab 2000 and their Chinese
systems are designed similarly to
Western ones making integration easier.
Pakistan has successfully integrated its
F-16s Mirage 3 and 5, JF17 Thunder and
J10C aircraft under a single data link
system link 17. Meanwhile, India
currently operates four separate data
links and is developing a fifth one
called B-Net through DRDO aiming to
unify its network ccentric capabilities.
France through Desalt Aviation, the
manufacturer of Rafal has argued that it
cannot share the source code due to
concerns over intellectual property and
proprietary defense technology.
According to French officials, the
development of the Rafal platform
involved years of intensive research in
substantial financial investment.
Sharing the code could jeopardize its
strategic advantage and defense export
market. While this argument may seem
technically valid, many Indian defense
analysts and political commentators are
viewing it as a diplomatic betrayal,
especially given the premium price India
paid for the jets and the portrayal of
France as a trusted defense
partner. The refusal puts a dent in
India's vision of strategic military
autonomy. If India needs to integrate
specific missiles or electronic warfare
suites during a crisis, it will now
require French approval and technical
involvement. This goes against the ethos
of the
atmirerbarat, self-reliant India
campaign, which emphasizes building and
controlling indigenous defense
capabilities. The Rafal deal has always
been a political flash point. When the
deal was signed in 2016, several
opposition parties, particularly the
Congress, raised concerns about inflated
prices and lack of transparency. With
France now declining to share critical
technological control, those earlier
objections appear to carry renewed
weight. India now faces two choices.
either renegotiate with France for
limited or monitored access to essential
parts of the source code or double down
on the development of indigenous
platforms like the TEDES MK2 or the
upcoming AMCA advanced medium combat
aircraft. Long-term strategic
independence lies in boosting domestic
R&D and ensuring future contracts
safeguard technological sovereignty. I
hope friends that you have understood
well. I have tried to explain it in very
simple words. Please do share your
valuable opinions in the comments.
That's all for today's update. Please
subscribe and like this video.