I wonder how the 10-day national
celebration in the Bed Empire is going.
Whether the people fully feel the joy of
victory and the greatness of Modi since
India crushed Pakistan in the border
conflict and France's Rafael fighter
jets enhanced by AI technology
outperformed Chinese equipment.
Shouldn't India with such great military
achievements pay the remaining balance
for the Raphael jets? The French have
repeatedly complained about India's
delayed payments. Now that India has won
the war, sending parliamentarians
everywhere to proclaim victory and God
media releasing numerous videos accusing
global media of ignoring India's
achievements. Well, we acknowledge India
crushed
Pakistan. So, the French are waiting for
the
payment. Yes, when doing business with
Indians, one rule must be remembered.
Full payment must be made before
shipment. Otherwise, once the goods
arrive in India, it's hard to say when
or if you'll receive the remaining
payment. Chambers of commerce in China's
Guang Dong and Ju Jang regions
constantly remind companies to be
cautious when shipping to India. This is
a hard lesson learned by Chinese
businesses after years of being
deceived. At the Canton Fair, Indian
clients requesting free samples or
asking merchants to provide lunch are
outright rejected. Yes, you wouldn't
believe it, but some Indians deceive
Chinese merchants into discussing
projects just to get a free lunch and
then disappear. For these anecdotes, you
can check my previous videos which
explain them in detail. In short,
Chinese businesses no longer invest in
factories in India to avoid being
targeted by the Indian government. Nor
do they ship goods before receiving
payment. Most Chinese manufacturers
require Indian clients to pay the full
amount or about 80% of the payment
before shipping. But in the information
age, do the French not know about
India's business reputation? Of course
not. The French are not selling weapons
to India for the first time and are well
aware of the Indian government's
international reputation. The French are
smart. They bribe Indian officials and
sell Raphael jets to India at three
times the price of an
F-35. Even if India pays only 30% of the
deposit, the French won't lose money. As
for the remaining balance, they'll
recover whatever they can. After the
IndiaPakistan air conflict broke out,
global media confirmed through various
channels that a Raphael jet was shot
down by
AJ10. Only Indian media insisted that
India achieved victory. A crushing one
at that. Originally, Dassau was worried
that the Indian government would default
and refuse to pay the remaining balance
for the Raphael Jets. Now, the
opportunity has come. The Indian
government and media for the sake of
vanity are heavily boasting about their
achievements and praising the Raphael's
excellent performance. As a result,
India has no reason to refuse or delay
paying the remaining
balance. In fact, India media's fake
news is only for self-entertainment.
The Indian Air Force's poor combat
capability has become a global
laughingstock. Mocked relentlessly by
netizens worldwide just like their space
docking which lacks video or image
evidence. They announced success under
global skepticism and claim to have
joined the space docking club. Yes,
India is obsessed with joining various
clubs such as the superpower club,
military power club, technology power
club, 5G leader club and AI technology
club. Honestly, Chinese people are quite
frustrated. We hope India removes China
from the member lists when promoting
these clubs as we don't want to be in
the same club as a boastful nation like
India. If there were a beggar club, the
Baret Empire would undoubtedly qualify
as it has half of the world's extremely
poor population. If there were a clown
club, the Baret Empire would surely be a
VIP as Modi and the BJP are undoubtedly
clown kings. If there were a fake news
club, India's Pocky Sharma would
definitely be the club queen with her
countless fake news reports.
Now is the time for India to uphold its
national reputation under the scrutiny
of global media, hurry up and pay the
remaining balance for the Raphael jets
and continue increasing procurement. Not
only should the air force equip more,
but the Navy should also buy in large
quantities, doubling the procurement to
ensure crushing Pakistan's J10 jets and
the upcoming J35 jets in the next
conflict.
By the way, you should know that
Pakistan is certain to equip China's J35
jets, which are fifth generation fighter
jets. At that time, China is likely to
equip them with PL17 or even PL21
missiles. When you use Raphael jets to
intercept these missiles, you can
deplete Pakistan's military budget
further as these new missiles are top
tier equipment of the Chinese Air Force,
far more expensive than the PL-15.
You don't need to keep working on your
fifth generation AMCA jet on PowerPoint.
Nor should you beg the US to sell F35
jets because Pocky Sharma said Raphael
jets have AI combat capabilities, can
automatically lock onto enemy targets,
and strike intelligently. In the face of
Raphael jets and the Bed Empire's
powerful AI combat capabilities, J10,
J35, PL-15, and PL17 are
insignificant. However, next time you
need to do better propaganda to make
people from other countries believe your
news instead of mocking you
relentlessly. After the next conflict, I
hope the Bard Empire holds a month-long
celebration, preferably broadcast
globally, so we can share the joy.